Eugene Gluhotorenko

Senior Software Engineer, TechLead

Minsk, Belarus

PROFILE

Software engineer with 9+ years experience in IT, focus on frontend development but have background in .NET and Node.js Passionate about programming, software engineering, data visualization and especially about creating rich frontend apps. My spare time I spend on reading popular science books, sport, traveling and developing open source.

EDUCATION

Belarusian University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.Sc | Computer Science, Network systems

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React, MobX, Redux, styled-components, PixiJS, Webpack, HTML, CSS, Git, Chrome DevTools, AngularJS and a lot of other libraries and tools.

EXPERIENCE

Software TechLead

CCDS | Oct 2019 → current

TypeScript React MobX Cornerstone.js DICOM Scrum / Agile

- Develop a viewer for visualization of medical data and ML model generated output
- Develop a platform for processing medical studies.

Senior Software Engineer

BGAMING / SoftSwiss | Apr 2018 → Oct 2019



- Develop game engine for multi-platform 2D games.
- Performance optimisation
- Writing server-side scripts for processing images and audio
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

Senior Software Engineer

MintData | Aug 2016 → Mar 2018

TypeScript React MobX MobX State Tree

- Develop a visual programming platform for creating real-time applications based on spreadsheets and visual GUI builder.
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

Lead Software Developer

CTDev | Oct 2013 → Aug 2016

JavaScript AngularJS Highchars D3.js Node.js Scrum / Agile

- Develop a news portal with recommendation engine for financial sector with a lot of data visualisation features: charts, graphs, markets statistics tables and etc.
- Writing gulp/grunt scripts for build system.
- Technical interviewing of new candidates

Senior Software Developer

EPAM Systems | Dec 2010 → Sep 2013



- Develop a platform for publishing financial apps
- HTML5 apps for the platform (Time series data charts, market/exchange data viewers and etc.)
- JavaScript API for third-party app developers.
- Develop back-end services.

BLOG ARTICLES

 How styled-components works: A deep dive under the hood Aug 2018

LINKS

Home page: e.gluhotorenko.comEmail: e.gluhotorenko@gmail.com

• Github: gevgeny

• Telegram: egluhotorenko

• LinkedIn: eugene-gluhotorenko